# Richard Hendriks

#### Programmer

**≅** About

☑ r.hendriks@piedpiper.com

(912) 555-4321

piedpiper.com

siliconHBO

♠ SiliconHBO

(o) siliconhbo

X Skills

#### Expert

Git-Ops/IAC

K8 Docker CI/CD

Observability Git

Frontend

React Pug/SASS

Typescript Node Express

Backend

Python Ruby GRPC

Kafka Protobuf

ETL Pipeline pSql/noSql

Redis TSDBs

#### Advanced

Project Management

Agile/Kanban Scrum Master

Jira Sheets/Excel

Task Decomposition

Technical Design

UML/C4 DDD EA

TOGAF

#### Experimenting

Experimenting

Solidity

Substrate (blockchain) Rust

VectorDBs

**A**■ Languages

Java C++ MIPS

Expert Typescript Advanced Bash/Shell SASS/CSS Experimenting Kotlin Rust Legacy

## Summarv

Richard hails from Tulsa. He has earned degrees from the University of Oklahoma and Stanford. (Go Sooners and Cardinals!) Before starting Pied Piper, he worked for Hooli as a part time software developer. While his work focuses on applied information theory, mostly optimizing lossless compression schema of both the length-limited and adaptive variants, his non-work interests range widely, everything from quantum computing to chaos theory. He could tell you about it, but THAT would NOT be a lengthlimited conversation!



#### Experience



### Pied Piper | CEO/President

2014-04-13 - Present

Pied Piper is a multi-platform technology based on a proprietary universal compression algorithm that has consistently fielded high Weisman Scores™ that are not merely competitive, but approach the theoretical limit of lossless compression.

- Build an algorithm for artist to detect if their music was violating copy right infringement laws
- Successfully won Techcrunch Disrupt
- Optimized an algorithm that holds the current world record for Weisman Scores

Hooli | Software Engineer

2013-01-01 - 2014-04-06

Worked on optimizing the backend algorithms for Hooli

#### Volunteer

Teacher

Global movement of free coding clubs for young people.

· Awarded 'Teacher of the Month'

## Education

**Stanford** | B.S | Computer Science

2011-06-01 - 2014-01-01

Palo Alto, C

**GPA 4.0** 

Machine Learning

• DB1101 - Basic SQL

• CS2011 - Java Introduction



## **Digital Compression Pioneer Award** | Techcrunch

There is no spoon.

## **Publications**

Hooli

Innovative middle-out compression algorithm that changes the way we store data.

## 66 References

**66** It is my pleasure to recommend Richard. That is all.

- Erlich Bachman



# Favorite Books

